Pablo Steven Rodriguez Ruiz. Mocoa, Colombia (GMT-5)

(+57)316 619 8398

Java Software Engineer

pablo.steven@hotmail.com

linkedin.com/in/pablostevenrodriguez

Java and python developer with 4+ years of experience in software engineering and programming using microservices architecture. Knowledge in the software development life cycle, team leadership for the implementation of professional software projects for prestigious companies in the financial sector and delivery sector. With experience in tools like Spring Boot, Hibernate, Databases, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Git, Scrum. Best Practices in horizontal and vertical scalability. Analytical mind, achievement orientation, passionate about development, best practices and keeps up to date with technology changes. Good interpersonal skills with customers and co-workers.

EXPERIENCE

(N1) ITAC sas.

Senior Engineer, Development Team Leader.. March, 2022 - Act.

- Implement and develop the PSE system for financial institutions in Colombia. Guide and lead the development team in the implementation of innovative solutions, with the best practice of SOUD principles and dean code.
- Achievements: Developed and implemented software solutions that improved the payment methods of companies in the financial sector. PSE solution increases the customer coverage 50% and improves their users experience.

Tech Stack: Java 11, Gradle, Spring Boot, Rest Api, Cassandra, Dynamo, Mongo, SQS, Redis, Amazon WebServices (AWS), Hibernate, JPA, Linux servers, Jira, Git, GitHub, Scrum, among others.

(N2) Global Networks Solutions.

Development Team Leader, Development Engineer. February, 2020 - March, 2022.

- Propose technological solutions to all the company's customers. Guide and lead the development team in the implementation of innovative solutions.
- Achievements: Developed and implemented software solutions that solved problems for companies in the financial, delivery and
 health sector such as Bancolombia, Davivienda, Efecty, Servientrega, Seguros Bolívar, Clínica Valle del Lili, among others; that solved
 communication problems with their customers (recovering 70% of thelostinteractionsofbusinessopportunities)andimprovingtheir
 users experience.
- Achievements: Worked with BOTs and AI Systems to improve the interaction time response; that ncreased business productivity of companies and improved digital transformation processes

Tech Stack: Java 8, Spring Boot, Rest Api, PostgreSQL, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Hibernate, JPA, Oracle DB, SQLServer, Linux servers, Jira, Git, GitHub, Scrum, among others.

(N3) JPT Consulting.

Software Developer. January, 2019 - November - 2019.

- Support the development of IoT Systems with innovative technologies to obtain real-time metrics from early warning systems and oil and gas systems. Guide and lead the development team in the implementation of innovative solutions.
- Achievements: Collaborate to develop an algorithm used to obtain the water cut in oil and gas. That solution solved problems for companies in oil sector such a Ecopetrol. That Improved the calculated of crude per m2.

Tech Stack: Java 8, Python 2, QT5, C++, JavaScript, Node Js, Rest Api, PostgreSQL, GitHub, Linux Servers.

(N3) Hispaintel Iberica.

Freelance Developer. January, 2021 – July, 2021.

- Developer of websites and business applications, using programming languages such as Java, JavaScript and other technologies. TI infrastructure service provider.
- Achievements: Designed and developed a scalable delivery note management system, under a doud architecture.

Tech Stack: Java 8, JSF, PrimeFaces, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, HTML5, CSS, Amazon Web Services (AWS), GitHub, Linux Servers.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Advanced: Java 8/11; Intermediate: JavaScript; Basic: Python, C++, c#.

Frameworks and Tools: Advanced: Spring Boot, PrimeFaces; Intermediate: Hibernate, JPA, Git, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes; Basic: Openshift, Azure.

Data Base: Advanced: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, DynamoDb; Intermediate: MongoDb, Cassandra Basic: Oracle, SQL Server, Kafka.

Agile: Scrum.

Languages: Advanced: English; Native: Spanish

EDUCATION

Universidad del Cauca, Electronics and telecommunications Engineer. 2012 - 2018 Universidad de Cataluña, Machine Learning Diplomat. October, 2021- April , 2022.